João Cavacos

Game Programmei

Hey there! I'm João Cavacos and I'm from Portugal. With dedicated experience in game development, my journey began in high school when I first delved into the fascinating world of coding. Since then, I've entered on a journey into creating games. I've completed my bachelor's degree studying Game Development at IPMAIA and I'm currently working at Blue Gravity Studios!

Porto, Portugal

linkedin.com/in/joão-cavacos-bb81231b6

(+351) 930593980

👿 joaocavacos.github.io/#/

github.com/joaocavacos

EDUCATION

Game Development

Instituto Politécnico da Maia, IPMAIA (Bachelor)

09/2019 - 07/2023

Porto, Portugal

WORK EXPERIENCE

Unity Programmer Blue Gravity Studios

04/2024 - Present Technologies: Unity and C# United Kingdom, Remote

Gameplay Programmer AstralShift

05/2023 - 10/2023 Technologies: Unity and C#

Portugal, Remote

Achievements/Tasks

- Worked on Little Goody Two Shoes (PC, PS5, XBOX, Switch):
- Developed and enhanced game functionalities, such as implementing and innovating new mechanics, assisting in designing the game flow, and fine-tuning existing mechanics;
- Sound design with FMOD integration: Implemented sound effects and background music in collaboration with a sound designer;
- Bug identification and fixing: Collaborated with the QA team using Jira to address reported issues and resolved them;
- Collaborated with the team to modify and adjust animation events in both cutscenes and maps, enhancing the visual storytelling of the game using the Unity Timeline.

Godot Software Engineer (Internship)

Fabamaq, Sistemas Informáticos S.A.

01/2022 - 06/2022 Technologies: Godot Engine, GDScript and C++ Porto, Portugal

Achievements/Tasks

- Active participation in "brainstorming" meetings in order to find the best solutions for the implementation, usability and appearance of casino games;
- Use of the Godot game engine to create visual interfaces and the respective associated algorithm for "Slots" games;
- Worked together with the art team, on a new company prototype developed by creating and adding new innovative functionalities in a new hardware requested by a client;
- Study and continuation of the development of state machines (and/or sub-state machines) that guarantee the base of joint operation for "Bingo" and "Spins" game types (C++).

Unity ProgrammerModal Interactive - Freelance

10/2020 - 06/2021 Technologies: Unity and C#

Porto, Portugal

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

The Loop (3D Psychological Horror) (02/2024 - 02/2024)

 Worked with a group of 4 for the MAD Game Jam 2024 (48h) where we won the best visual prize! Programmed the loop states, collectable system and UI, using C# and Unity.

Don't D13 (3D 1v1 Party Game) (11/2023 - Present)

 Worked with a group of 5 for the Invictvs Game Jam 2023 (48h)! Programmed 3 minigames, game states and implemented SFX/Music, using C# and Unity.

Dark Memories (3D Survival Horror) (09/2021 - 11/2021)

Solo developer/programmer using C# and Unity Engine.

PrayBack (2D Topdown Beat-em-up) (10/2021 - 10/2021)

 Worked with a group of 5 for the Invictvs Game Jam 2021 (48h) using agile methodologies, crowning us 2nd place! Programmed the Enemy AI, and the game UI using C# and Unity

The Apprentice (2D Topdown) (11/2020 - 11/2020)

Solo developer/programmer using C# and Unity Engine.

Knight Typer (2D Sidescroller) (10/2020 - 10/2020)

Solo developer/programmer using C# and Unity Engine.

CERTIFICATES

Unity Junior Programmer (04/2022 - 06/2022)

The Unity Junior Programmer Pathway validates skills and competencies to be a proficient junior programmer writing scripts in C#

Unreal Engine 5 C++ Development (04/2023 - 05/2023)

Understanding of the C++ programming language and its implementation within Unreal Engine 5, which enabled me to build highly optimized game systems and features.

C++ Course (Codecademy) (01/2024 - 01/2024)

Understanding of the C++ programming language as well as some uses in real life applications.

LANGUAGES

Portuguese Native or Bilingual Proficiency English Full Professional Proficiency